

Yee Feng Hsu

zaken520@gmail.com (852) 9273-7829

Profile

Worked in software development for 15+ years. Started in Silicon Valley, then moved to HK. Majority time was a C++ developer but recently moved to C# .NET. Consider myself a Fullstack developer with some frontend knowledge. Very good with design patterns, algorithms, web apps, Fintech, and Blockchain.

Certified SCRUM Master using Agile methodology, CI/CD, and Test Driven Development.

Education

San Francisco State University - B.S. Computer Science. 2002.

Technical Skills

Modern C/C++ 11/17/19

OOP & Design Patterns

Agile, CI/CD, TDD, SCRUM

MySQL, Store Procedures TCP/IP Sockets, Boost ASIO

HTML5, CSS3, JS, Web 2.0

Data Structures & Algorithms

MSSQL, T-SQL, Views

Blockchain, DLT, PoW, PoS

Professional Working History

UNDISCLOSED FINTECH CO.

Senior C++/C# .NET System Analyst

January 2019 - Present Causeway Bay, Hong Kong

Quarry Bay, Hong Kong

• Managed high-frequency FIX trading platform written in C++ 17, Boost ASIO

- Developed new derivatives trading platform in C# .NET Core, WPF, MVVM, Prism
- Wrote various micro-services in both C++/C#, C++/CLI, Windows Services

Avanade

November 2017 - December 2018

Senior .NET Consultant

- Provided .NET consultancy to various fortune 500 clients, including Accenture
- Used C# Web API 2.0, MVC, Message Queue, Asynchronous calls, MSSQL, MSUnit
- Worked in Agile/SCRUM methods including CI/CD, TDD, BDD, SpecFlow, refactoring
- Helped in DevOps, releases, Jenkins, JIRA, Confluence, Selenium, Microsoft 365 dynamics

Concord Pacific Satellite Technologies Ltd.

November 2015 - June 2017

Kowloon, Hong Kong

Lead Analyst Programmer

- Lead cross-regional Agile team to develop GPS Fleet Management SAAS solution
- Lead front-end development team using Javascript, JQuery, AngularJS, JSON, Bootstrap • Revamped SOA backend using C# .NET, MySQL, TCP/IP sockets, threads, SOAP & WCF APIs
- Introduced to team: Agile, TDD, NUnit, MantisBT, SVN, GIT, Skype, Google Maps

Global Talent Services Ltd. - Unisys Hong Kong Ltd.

January 2015 - November 2015

Kwun Tong, Hong Kong

Contrator / Developer • Independant contractor implemented banking Signature Web Viewer Verification system

• Fullstack using VB/C# .NET, WCF, HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, JQuery, AJAX, REST, MSSQL • Part of full SDLC in various phases, staging, SIT, UAT, then LIVE

Sungard Global Trading Ltd.

August 2011 - December 2014

- Participated in development of real-time trading platform in WIN32 C++
- Worked with various teams OMS, FIX, Market Data, Market Access, and Exchange PMs
- Debugged trading algorithms, strategies on cash, equities and derivative market • Cross functional teams using Agile, TDD, and daily SCRUM to meet sprint targets

QVIVO Ltd.

October 2010 - August 2011

Sheung Wan, Hong Kong

Sr. Software Engineer

- Developed cross platform media player in standard C++/STL, Boost library, threads
- Integrated Facebook API, cURL, AWS Cloud, IPC and memory sharing libraries
- Used Agile, TDD, Google unit testing, FFMpeg, Scaleform GFX, DirectX, OpenGL

Concord Pacific Satellite Technologies Ltd.

November 2008 - October 2010

Sr. Software Engineer

• Web Traffic & GPS related fleet management software control

Kowloon, Hong Kong

- Embedded media player development using WinCE C++ MFC, WIN32, COM, HTTP, FTP
- Developed backend in C Linux, sockets, POSIX threads, MySQL tunning

OPSWAT, Inc. Sr. Software Engineer

April 2005 - October 2008 San Francisco, USA

• Part of team to develop Antivirus/Antispyware/Firewall SDK

- Implemented API library in OOP C++, C#, Java, PHP, HTTP/FTP/SMTP, XML, STL
- Integrated computer security, encryption, hashing MD5, SHA256, digital signatures

One Share of Stock, Inc.

August 2003 - July 2004 San Francisco, USA

SEO Specialist

• Search Engine Optimization to place within Top-10 on Google and Yahoo

• Developed website using ASP/VBS, HTML/CSS/JavaScript and SQL • Managed Webtrends, Linux, Bash scripts, SQL Servers and Apache

Mendocino. San Francisco Sales, Inc.

August 2002 - August 2003 San Francisco, USA

Web Developer • Designed intranet using HTML, JS, CGI, XML/XSLT, and Photoshop

• Engineered inventory management & ERP system

May 1998 - September 1998

San Francisco, USA

Club-i - Cyber cafe

Web Developer (Internship)

• Designed intranet using HTML, JS, CGI, and Photoshop

• Assisted customers on using PC, email, web browsers, printing